<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
   <properties>
      <author email="linnet@nospam.users.sourceforge.net">Jesper Kamstrup Linnet</author>

      <title>Usage</title>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <section name="Activation of the Open Implementation action">
            <p>
            Activating the Open Implementation action is done by pressing Alt+F3 in the Java editor
            (this shortcut may be customized in the preferences.)
            The plugin may also be activated in the editor's context menu (the name of the action is "Open Implementation".)
            </p>
            <p>
            If the cursor is located on a method name, Eclipse jumps to the implementing method(s). If the cursor is located on
            a an interface type (either the type itself or an instance), Eclipse jumps to the implementing type(s).
            </p>
            <p>
            If no matching classes are found, a message is shown in the status line.
            </p>

         <subsection name="Example">
            <p>
            In the code snippet below...
            </p>
            <source>
               Collection elements = ...
               elements.add("Hello");
            </source>
            <p>
            If you place the cursor on <i>add</i> and invoke the plugin, a dialog with list of implementing classes is shown.
            In this dialog you can select the method to jump to.
            </p>
            <p>
            <img src="images/dialog.png" title="Dialog for selecting the implementor" alt="Dialog for selecting the implementor" />
            </p>
            <p>If only one matching class is found, the plugin jumps directly to the class without showing the dialog.</p>
            <p>In the example above, you could also have placed the cursor on the elements variable. Invoking the "Open Implementation"
            function in this case would jump to the implementation class itself.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>

      <section name="Activation of the Open Interface action">
            <p>
            Activating the Open Interface action is done by pressing Ctrl+Alt+F3 in the Java editor
            (this shortcut may be customized in the preferences.)
            The plugin may also be activated in the editor's context menu (the name of the action is "Open Interface".)
            </p>
            <p>
            If the cursor is located on a method name in a class implementing an interface, Eclipse jumps to the declaration of the 
            method in the interface. If the cursor is located on a a class (either the type itself or an instance), Eclipse jumps to the
            interface type(s).
            </p>
            <p>
            If no matching interfaces are found, a message is shown in the status line.
            </p>

         <subsection name="Example">
            <p>
            In the code snippet below...
            </p>
            <source>
               package dk.kamstruplinnet.test;

               public class Test implements ITest {

                   public void someMethod() {
                       // TODO
                   }
               }
            </source>
            <p>
            If you place the cursor on <i>someMethod</i> and invoke the plugin, a dialog with list of interfaces declaring the method is shown.
            In this dialog you can select the interface to jump to.
            </p>
            <p>
            If only one matching interface is found, the plugin jumps directly to the interface without showing the dialog. 
            </p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>

