<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
   <properties>
      <author email="linnet@nospam.users.sourceforge.net">Jesper Kamstrup Linnet</author>
      <author email="deerwood@nospam.users.sourceforge.net">Georg Rehfeld</author>

      <title>Usage</title>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <section name="Usage">
         <subsection name="Overall">
            <ul>
               <li>Quickmarks are Workspace global by default, but you can 
                  change that to have one Set of Quickmarks per Project, Folder 
                  or Document.</li>
               <li>A Quickmark remembers the current selection completely by 
                  default, but you can change that to only remember the start 
                  of the selection or the line of the selection.</li>
               <li>There are 10 available Quickmarks (0-9). Only one instance 
                  of each Quickmark number can be set by default, but you can 
                  have more (by accident or intention).</li>
               <li>As duplicate Quickmarks (with the same number) <b>can</b> 
                  exist by accident or intention, the plugin handles jumping to 
                  the dups by toggling through them. Setting a new, already 
                  duplicated mark is "fool proof" by default.</li>
               <li>The Quickmarks are persisted across sessions, enabling you 
                  to quickly jump to the locations you were at last time.</li>
               <li>There is a menu for manipulating and jumping to 
                  Quickmarks.</li>
               <li>Quickmarks are visible/jumpable to in task and bookmark 
                  view, but you are able to change that too. But see the notes 
                  in the feature docs, if you are an Eclipse 3 user!</li>
               <li>A Quickmark is indicated by an icon with the corresponding 
                  number in the vertical annotation bar. Again, see the notes 
                  in the feature docs, if you are an Eclipse 3 user!</li>
               <li>The Quickmarks description in the views/when hovering is 
                  good configurable.</li>
               <li>The plugin comes with detailed and illustrated online 
                  documentation including context sensitive help.</li>
               <li>You can even switch to another style ("M" company style, 
                  always toggling through Quickmarks, unlimited number of 
                  marks). Or you may have best of both worlds.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Please be sure to have read the "readme.html" and/or the online 
               docs coming with the plugin.</p>
         </subsection>
         
         <subsection name="Activating the plugin">
            <p>In order to activate the plugin, you need to enable Window / 
               Customize Perspective / Other -&gt; Quickmarks Both Styles.</p>
         </subsection>
         
         <subsection name="Setting quickmarks">
            <p>Quickmarks are set using Ctrl+Shift+[0-9] (the keyboard 
               shortcuts can be changed in Window / Preferences / Workbench / 
               Keys -&gt; Navigate.)</p>
            <p> If a quickmark with the same number already exists, it is moved 
               to the new location by default (unless there are duplicates 
               already, then another duplicate is added by default). If the 
               specific quickmark already exists in the current location, that 
               quickmark is removed always.</p>
         </subsection>
   
         <subsection name="Jumping to quickmarks">
            <p>You jump to a quickmark by pressing Alt+[0-9]. If the quickmark 
               is not in the active file, the corresponding editor is activated 
               (and the file is loaded if necessary).</p>
         </subsection>
         
         <subsection name="On our todo list">
            <p>In this order:</p>
            <ol>
               <li>Add an undo feature when moving quickmarks (in case 
                  important positions were lost). Current plan is to have the 
                  old quickmarks recreated to invisible markers on move of a 
                  quickmark for some time and have a special 'Quickmark 
                  History' view to jump to them and then possibly recreate a 
                  normal quickmark there.</li>
            </ol>
         </subsection>

         <subsection name="Things to note">
            <p>In some editors, you can't set marks at all, including by means 
               of this plugin. This is particularly in the PDE-related editors 
               (build.properties editor, plugin.xml editor etc). Other cases 
               are editors opened via "Jump to Definition" (F3) and presenting 
               you a class file, or files opened from the "Plug-ins" view. In 
               the latter cases these editors also appear as read only. 
               Although in all mentioned cases setting marks would be usefull 
               too, Eclipse does not offer that functionality. So only an 
               appropriate message is shown.</p>
            <p>The versions 1.0.11 and 3.0.2 were implemented mainly by Georg Rehfeld. 
               Thanks to Jesper for the initial version and all further 
               support!</p>
            <p>The plugin/package name has changed from 1.0.1 (formerly 
               <code>dk.kampstruplinnet.quickmarks</code>) to 1.0.10 (now 
               <code>net.sourceforge.eclipsetools.quickmarks</code>). So be 
               sure to remove <code>dk.kampstruplinnet.quickmarks_xxx</code> 
               plugins when installing this variant to avoid conflicts (does 
               not apply to Eclipse 2.1, but only Eclipse 3.x).</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
